JUJUTSU KAISEN
The Culling Game Part 1
In Japan, 99.9% of Criminal Trials End in a Guilty Verdict
I owned a cat.
Continue.
A cop suddenly started speaking to me.
Then there were two, then three of them.
I thought, "If they take me in now,
my cat is going to die."
My place doesn't allow us to own them.
So I was the only one who knew about it.
In Morioka City, Iwate Prefecture,
in March of 2016,
two people—
a young girl and her mother—
were found fatally stabbed
in their own home.
The Morioka Prosecutor's Office
indicted Keita Oe, who lived nearby,
on charges of felony murder and robbery.
The events leading to
his arrest were thus:
Oe fled during police questioning
by officers on patrol,
Hey! Stop!
and after police chased
him into his home,
the officers who chased him discovered
a blade with blood on it,
and then arrested him
in flagrante delicto.
Later DNA analysis
There he is!
Come on, behave!
revealed the blood on the blade
matched the victims' DNA.
Stop struggling!
Oe consistently denied all
culpability for the crime.
On the blade collected
as evidence, he insisted...
I just picked it up.
It wasn't mine.
That's a bit hard to believe, isn't it?
I mean, he refused the questioning
because he felt guilty, right?
No. He was previously a victim
of wrongful questioning
because an acquaintance of his
was using drugs in the past.
You're saying that traumatized him?
Even so, "I picked it up"?
A bloody kitchen knife? Why?
He claims he was planning to
turn it in to the police later.
"Later"?!
I know.
His claims are all hard to believe.
But when you consider Oe's background—
the fact that he works as a live-in
employee at a non-profit organization—
it starts sounding plausible.
A non-profit?
They work with the elderly
who have no place to go,
primarily running a shelter and providing
support for their independent living.
Oe's job was taking care
of the elderly there.
However, they didn't pay him a wage.
They only supplied him with goods
like groceries, boxed lunches,
and the occasional New Year's
gift of pocket money.
Yet despite that,
they collected 50,000 yen
a month from him as rent.
Brutal.
Apparently, quite a few of the
residents have prior records.
Furthermore, the reason he was delayed in
turning over the weapon he found was...
The rules say we can't call
any cop cars or ambulances.
Because they'd bother the neighbors.
Higuruma Law Office
That organization sounds
kinda shady, doesn't it?
Yeah.
It's extremely close to
being outright illegal.
We've already seen an increase
in suspiciously managed NPOs
since the earthquake relief funds
started flowing into this region.
So it's not surprising the murder
weapon was just lying around.
There's a good possibility Oe's innocent.
First, we'll investigate the
organization's activities and tax filings,
then run background checks
on all the residents.
I'll focus on getting
information out of Oe.
You handle the investigation, Shimizu.
You're dumping a huge job like
that on me out of the blue?
Could you take care of his cat, too?
The cat?!
The commission for public defense cases
is low, despite how much work they take.
The public assumes he's guilty, too.
Plus, there's no suspended
sentence in murder cases,
and he could receive the death penalty.
There's nothing to gain here.
Jeez, Higuruma-san! Why did you
go and accept a case like this?
It's fine every now and then.
If we stuck to easy work,
our skills would dull.
It's more than every now and then!
You're saying your thoughts out loud.
Sounds like Higuruma-kun
hasn't changed then.
It's rough when an independent
lawyer isn't in it for the money.
At least it's not so bad that I'm being
told to run a café on the side like you.
But when you say he hasn't changed,
you mean Higuruma-san's
always been like this?
Hm? No.
I think he actually used to be worse.
Huh?
Back when he was with us,
he was in charge of a case of
reckless driving resulting in injury.
Oh, a drunk driving one.
The defendant was nineteen,
and his coworkers had coerced him into
both the drinking and the driving.
However, those involved all
aligned their stories,
and he wasn't able to prepare
money for a settlement,
nor were we able to get
him a suspended sentence.
Liar!
You said they'd find me innocent!
You told him you'd manage to get
a suspended sentence, though,
not an innocent verdict.
Have you learned your lesson now?
Quit being a criminal defense
lawyer for impossible cases.
Trying to save the weak
may be a noble endeavor,
but there's a limit to what
lawyers like us can do
without understanding from
the courts and prosecutors.
Oh, I want to ride that!
It's not worth continuing when
your clients resent you.
They're at the end of their rope,
both mentally and financially.
I can't blame them for lashing out at me.
But what about your mental
state, Higuruma-kun?
I...
We find the defendant...
innocent.
We actually won this case?
Not yet.
They'll appeal right away.
The Morioka Mother-Child Murder Incident
Questionable Innocent Verdict.
"It Was Bought"
Former Judge Comments on Crooked Lawyer's Statements
The verdict was innocent.
Guess even murderers go free
if they can pay up.
How much did he dump on this...
The law is dead. Prosecutors are useless.
Refusing to Accept the Current Ruling,
They Have Appealed Seeking A Revision
Morioka Prosecutor's Office
The prosecution has...
Nothing stolen was found
in Oe-san's room.
There was another person in the same NPO
who went missing right after the crime.
The fact that you were caught on a
convenience store's security camera feed
during the time of the crime determined
from the corpse played a major role, too.
Good thing you don't cook
for yourself, Oe-san!
Counselor Higuruma...
Thank you so much.
No need for "Counselor."
Besides, we're not in the clear yet.
We still have the second trial.
I worked hard, too.
That's not what I mean.
Thank you for believing me!
Appeal Trial (Second Trial)
Guilty. Life Sentence.
While defense lawyers have to work
with limited budgets and manpower,
prosecutors can pour manpower and
taxpayer money into digging up evidence.
That's fine. That's how the system works.
However,
the prosecutors didn't submit any new
evidence during the second trial.
The judge recognized
their absurd claim that
"there's no reason to suspect the
missing person of the crime,"
and they overturned the verdict.
The highest court is always the
bottleneck for a third trial.
Most final appeals are
turned away at the door.
It's challenging to even
get a proper trial there.
This trial was destined for a
guilty verdict from the start.
Why are you
looking at me that way?
But what about your mental
state, Higuruma-kun?
I'm not trying to tout the
ideal of saving the weak.
It's just always gone against my nature
to leave things alone when
I feel like they're wrong.
I've just never managed
to fix that habit.
The goddess of justice blinds her sight
to maintain fairness under the law,
and people turn a blind eye to all
kinds of things to protect themselves.
But I don't want to brush away the
hands clinging to me for help,
so I want to keep my eyes open, at least.
If there are any objections
to today's trial,
submit your final appeal in writing
within fifteen days, including today.
Higuruma-san?
Everyone come back.
We're having a retrial.
Culling Game Player
Hiromi Higuruma
Higuruma is in...
...Shinjuku.
...Ikebukuro.
Got it?
Shinjuku?
I hope Itadori is heading there, too.
Ikebukuro, huh?
I wonder if Fushiguro's there, too.
Isn't she a little late?
When is that girl
going to bring me my next sucker?
Episode 55
Tokyo No. 1 Colony, Part 2
Huh? Wh-What?
Oh, no, no.
Not like that at all.
Hey, what are you doing?
Like this! This!
R-Right.
Why are you keeping quiet?
You're better off laughing!
Come on, come on!
Oh, dear. What did I tell you?
What's your problem?
What's your problem?!
Not that I actually told you.
There you go.
But why can't you understand?
What's your problem?!
Are you an idiot?!
These guys aren't that smart or athletic,
but they're brimming with pride.
You just have to match their vibe and
joke around so you don't hurt that pride.
Then you won't get targeted
by anyone else, either.
And you can occasionally
enjoy a good time, too.
Stop it.
Here comes another idiot.
Is that uniform from West Middle?
You're a middle schooler?
You weren't showing respect, were you?
So you need to
learn a lesson!
Huh?
No violence!
Come here!
What about you?
Culling Game Player
M-Me?
Yuji Itadori
Rin Amai
Hey.
What?
You aren't planning to go through
Ikebukuro to reach Shinjuku, are you?
That area's rich with supplies.
We're more likely to
encounter other Players.
There are two reasons for going this way.
The route is easy to follow,
and I have a base nearby.
At least let me take a shower.
I haven't gotten much
rest since yesterday.
Higuruma uses this theater as his base.
Assuming he hasn't moved, that is.
Cool!
You've been a big help! Thanks!
Oh, h-h-hold on!
What?
Are you seriously going?
I'd rather reunite with my friend
first, but we're in a hurry.
I haven't met Higuruma myself,
but he once beat Haba-san to a pulp.
Then I'll be fine!
I beat that propeller head, too,
so I'll at least be able to run away.
Maybe so
See you later!
Say it!
Say it, man!
You should stop doing this!
I'm sorry,
Itadori.
Higuruma? Oh...
Sorry, but I'm Reggie.
She deceived you.
Don't give me that look.
I'm not frightened at all.
Just so you know, Reggie—
Stop talking.
Oho?
We're wasting time.
Who's there?
What are you doing over there?
I could ask you that.
Have you ever taken a bath
while in your clothes?
Never.
It feels better than I expected.
Right.
Back when I was in elementary school,
I loved our classes on
swimming in clothes.
So many things have stopped
mattering lately,
so I've been challenging myself to
try things I assumed I shouldn't do.
I've basically gone off the
rails after hitting my mid-30s.
Is that funny?
It's kind of amusing.
You're Higuruma, right?
In the flesh.
I want to talk.
Hold on. Wait, wait.
I'm a lawyer.
Talking to me will incur a consultation
fee of 5,000 yen every half hour.
Huh?!
I'm kidding.
I just wanted to try acting
like a nasty lawyer for once.
I see.
What's this guy doing?
You have 100 points, right?
He's not a past sorcerer
who's been incarnated.
He's a modern sorcerer whose
technique was activated!
We can talk it out!
There's room for negotiation!
Oh, yeah. You pass.
Huh?
That's enough. I can tell now.
That's quite the shikigami.
You're strong, right?
If you were weak, I'd just
kill you as another mark.
But you're good.
Let's work together.
What gives?!
I never heard about this!
What are you getting at?
How much do you know
about this Culling Game?
It's a ritual, right?
It uses the cursed energy of
the Players inside the barriers
to ferry the people of
Japan to the other side
and change them into something inhuman.
Guess I should stay quiet
about Tengen-sama.
Oh? Do you know Kenjaku, then?
I knew there'd be one!
A sorcerer connected to Kenjaku!
Uh, so, to be frank,
we want to stop the Culling Game.
Er, time out.
When I say "stop it," I mean we want
to negate the compulsory killing.
Please let us use your 100 points
to add a rule toward that end.
Allow me to be frank, as well.
I refuse.
Is that another joke?
No.
I just sense potential
in the Culling Game.
Complete Book of the Six Codes
Sometimes the law is powerless.
But what about the rules
of this Culling Game?
If the power I've been granted is real,
then those rules must be, too.
What you just said about Players'
cursed energy being used?
That's probably a bluff.
What?
Well, less of a bluff,
and more Plan B or C.
I have three reasons.
The number of Players.
The strength gap between Players.
The barriers' rules.
If roughly 1,000 people were equally
split up between the ten Colonies,
that would be 100 per Colony.
But among the Players are sorcerers
like Kashimo or Higuruma,
who are much stronger than the rest.
These two alone have already
culled sixty sorcerers.
There's probably one like
them in each Colony.
So the weak are weeded out early on,
and the Culling Game
will reach a stalemate?
I certainly did sense that.
The Colony has been too quiet.
It already has.
At least here in Tokyo No. 1.
On top of that, there's the teleportation
when people enter the Colony.
It serves to spread them out,
but its main goal is likely to encourage
an early second awakening
of modern sorcerers.
There are some who die during
the teleportation, too.
If he was really trying to use
the Players' cursed energy,
he would want the greatest
number of sorcerers
to fight for the longest time possible.
What if people who broke the
rules were punished by physics,
without any need for indictments,
prosecutions, or arguments at trials?
Wouldn't that be wonderful?
I'll acknowledge there are
issues with the current rules,
but I want to watch over the system
serving as a basis for this game.
It won't do for it to end too soon.
I'd especially love to witness
the stripping of a technique
2: Players breaching the first rule
shall be stripped of their technique.
8:  Players who do not show a change in points
within 19 days of joining or acquiring points
shall be stripped of their technique.
mentioned in Rule 2 and 8 at least once.
It's better for the rules if
being stripped means death, too.
The Culling Game itself is a ritual.
If we take too long,
every person in this nation will die.
That's a lie.
The Culling Game insists
on its own permanence.
I don't really get that part, either!
Let me rephrase it, then.
Let me use your 100 points, Higuruma!
Have you ever killed someone
who ticked you off?
It feels much better than I expected.
A shikigami?!
Higuruma has 100 points.
He might have killed
twenty sorcerers already.
I can't leap in recklessly.
I'll go on defense,
but I'll be ready to
respond to any attack!
Domain Expansion.
Deadly Sentencing.
The rules' idea of continuation is
just a cover for the real plan.
Mark my words.
When only the strong remain,
Kenjaku is going to drop
a bomb on the game,
and the Culling Game
will fulfill its purpose.
Please have a seat.
Thank you for inviting me here.
Now, make your argument.
What happens if I'm judged guilty?
Judgeman, please begin.
You mean I can lie?
You get one chance to make a statement.
I can't control cursed energy!
How can he hold his own against
me without cursed energy?
I want a retrial! One more time!
Next Episode
Tokyo No. 1 Colony, Part 3